(フリド)フン…。
(ソラ)お前 本当に 里のヤツらを…。
Are you... really... going to
kill everyone in the village?
(フリド)あぁ 一人残らずな。
Yeah. Every single one.
それでこそ 火ノ国の再生は
なされる。
It will allow us to achieve the restoration
of the Land of Fire.
(ソラ)玉を… 火ノ国の玉を
なくすことが➡
Wasn't removing
the Land of Fire king...
お前たちの… いや 父さんの
義だったんじゃねえのか!?
your, I mean, my father's cause?
なんで 関係ねえヤツらまで
死なせなくちゃならねえんだ！
Why do people totally uninvolved
have to die?!
関係なくない。
They are involved.
玉がなくなっても
それを信じるヤツらがいる限り➡
As long as there are people alive
who believe in the Hokage,
火ノ国が
ひとつになったとは言えない。
the Land of Fire cannot become one.
わかるか？ お前のオヤジはな➡
Do you understand?
Your father was killed by Asuma
who believed in the Hokage.
火影を信じるアスマに 殺されたんだ。
やっかいなのは 玉じゃない。
The king isn't the problem.
それを信じる者たちだ。
The problem is those
who believe in the king.
彼らがいる限り 玉など➡
As long as they're around,
a king can be replaced
over and over again.
いくらでも
すげ替えることができる。
お前のオヤジは
そこのところを間違えた。
That's where your father
was mistaken...
(ソラ)間違えた…？
Mistaken...?
なくすべきは 玉じゃない 歩だ。
It's not the king that needs
to be gotten rid of.
It's the pawn!
(フリド)里の者 全員根絶やしにして
はじめて 玉を潰せる。
The king can be crushed only after
eradicating everyone in the village.
火ノ国を 真に統一することが
できるんだ。
Then the Land of Fire
can truly be unified.
雷夢雷人…
４つのいかづちが揃ったとき➡
Limelight...
When the four sources
of lightning come together,
すべてが ゼロになる。
everything goes back to zero.
そのときこそ 成就されるんだ。
That is the time when all
our aspirations...
(フリド)オレたちの願いが…。
will be fulfilled.
《フウカ フエン フドウ
彼らの道を守ってくれ。
Fouka, Fuen, Fudo.
Protect their paths.
死者にして術者
キタネ ナウマ トウウ セイトの４人の道を》
Protect the paths of
the dead Jutsu casters...
Kitane, Nauma, Tou'u and Seito.
雷夢雷人の準備ができた時点で
オレたちは 里を脱する。
Once the preparations for
the Limelight have been completed,
we will get out of the village.
お前も 一緒にな。
Along with you.
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Everyone's Struggle
to the Death
(ゲンマ)チッ どうやら あの土の山に
カラクリが ありそうだな。
It appears the trick lies in
that mountain of dirt!
(エビス)そうですね
ここ数日に襲った村の土を➡
You're right.
They summoned the earth from
the villages they attacked
埋葬された村人と ともに
口寄せした。
over these past several days
along with the buried villagers.
(ゲンマ)その 埋葬された村人を➡
So they're bringing the buried villagers
back to life one after another
転生術で 次々と
よみがえらせてるってわけか。
with a Reanimation Jutsu, huh?
(コテツ)冗談じゃねえ！
Give me a break.
How the hell many people
did they kill?
(イズモ)いったい 何人殺したんだ!?
Expansion Jutsu!
(チョウジ)倍化の術！
(チョウジ)腕～！
Arm!
これじゃ キリがないよ。
This is endless.
(キバ)チッ！ なんて数だ！
There's so many of them.
At this rate, the village will be buried
with the dead.
(リー)このままじゃ
里が 死人で埋まってしまいます！
The number of enemy units
is continuing to grow.
敵 死人部隊は
大門付近で増殖中➡
The reinforcement unit has joined up,
増援部隊が合流したものの➡
but it is all they can do to keep
the enemy from advancing
商店街に進行させないように
するのが➡
to the shopping district.
今のところ 精一杯です。
(綱手)そうか…。
I see...
Fifth Hokage,
please let me go to the field.
(シカマル)現場に行かせてくださいよ
五代目。
こんなところで
頭をひねってても➡
I won't be able to come up with anything
by trying to work this out in my head.
何も思いつきゃしませんしね。
オレのガラじゃねえ。
It's not in my nature.
わかった。
やるだけやってみます。
Fine...
I'll do what I can.
頼んだぞ。
I'm counting on you.
はい。
Yes, ma'am.
(フウカ)
フフフフ… いい格好だねぇ。
You look good like that...
勇ましいボウヤ。
You courageous boy...
その体を私にくれるなら
助けてあげてもいいわよ。
I can save you if you give
that body of yours to me.
I don't have a single thing
to give you!
(ナルト)テメエなんかにやるものは
１つもねぇ！
Beat it, you old hag!
うせろ クソババア!!
I see...
そう…。
You horrible kid...
憎たらしい子…。
フリドからは 殺さぬ程度にと
言われていたけれど…。
Furido told me to keep you alive...
(フウカ)誰にだって
失敗はあるわよね。
But everyone makes mistakes.
Lightning Style:
Electric Needle Spark!
雷遁 被雷針!!
ぐわぁ～っ!!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術!!
フッ… さすがにしぶといわね。
Tenacious, as expected.
I can't afford to be wasting time here.
こんなところで
時間つぶしてるヒマはねえんだよ！
Then I'll settle things for you!
だったら ケリをつけてあげるわよ！
Die!
(フドウ)死ねや!!
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
(ヤマト)木遁 木錠壁！
Stop hiding!
こそこそ 隠れやがって!!
うおおぉっ!!
That's right...
(フドウ)そうだったな…。
テメエも 土遁使いだったな。
You're also an Earth Style user...
Then let's find out... who's better.
(フドウ)なら…➡
どっちが上か勝負だ。
Earth Style: Falling Earth Spears!
土遁 土隆槍!!
It seems my body was
a bit harder than rock.
岩よりも オレの体のほうが
ちょっと硬かったようだな。
(サクラ)ここは…。
What is this place?
Anyway, I've got to get out of here.
ともかく ここから出なくっちゃ。
No! Stop!
(サクラ)やめて!!
Can't you forget about this?
(アスマ)やめにすることは
できねえのかな？
(キタネ)
あぁ… できないな。
No, I can't...
I liked you.
(アスマ)オレはお前さんが
好きだったぜ。
(キタネ)オレもだよ。
Me, too.
And yet...
(アスマ)なのにな…。
お前を殺さなければ
ならないとはな…。
I never thought...
I'd have to kill you...
Lightning Style: Lightning Bind!
雷遁 雷縛り！
(キタネ)やめた 生かしといてやるよ。
I won't bother. I'll let you live.
I don't have the time to
be dealing with you...
お前の相手をしている
ヒマがないからな。
キタネ！
Kitane!
Wait...
待て…。
くっ…。
《キタネ…》
Kitane...
そろそろ 彼らが たどり着く。
Soon, they should be arriving
at the Promised Land
雷夢雷人発動の 約束の地へ…。
for the activation of Limelight...
(ソラ)ダメだ。
No!
I won't let you...
この里は… この里のヤツらは➡
kill the people of this village!
殺させない！
(ソラ)この里は… この里のヤツらは
I won't let you...
kill the people of this village!
I hate Asuma...
But what you are doing, it's...
アスマは憎い
だが それとこれとは…。
お前も オヤジと一緒か…。
So you're just like your father, huh?
Wha--?!
なっ…！ うわぁ！
(ソラ)この…。
You jerk...
ソラ しようがねえなぁ お前。
You're pathetic, Sora.
嫌われもんが
ちょっと優しくされちまうと➡
This is what happens
when those shunned by others...
are treated a little kindly...
これだもんな。
なんだと…。
What did you say?
It was the same with
your father, too...
(フリド)お前のオヤジも そうだった。
I will smash all of that foolishness!
その甘さが すべてを ブチ壊す！
It is exactly that naïve thinking
that ruins the Land of Fire!
その甘さが 火ノ国を ダメにする！
その甘さが この里を生かし➡
It's what gives life to this village
and kills those with a soul!
心あるものたちを殺す！ 違うか!!
Am I right?
お前も オヤジのように死にたいか！
Do you want to die
like your father did?!
(ソラ)ぐあぁ～！
Sakura-chan...
サクラちゃん…。
Sakura-chan.
サクラちゃん。
ナルト？
Naruto?
You're okay now, Sakura-chan.
サクラちゃん もう大丈夫だってばよ。
敵は？
What about the enemy?
The walls were covered with moths...
壁が 蛾で覆われて➡
襲ってきて…。
And they attacked me...
ハハハ… 大丈夫。
It's okay, Sakura-chan. You must've had
quite a frightening experience.
サクラちゃん
よっぽど怖い目に遭ったんだね。
But don't worry...
でも もう安心して…。
I'll set your mind at ease.
ボクが 楽にしてあげるよ。
Why are you running?
なんで逃げるのさ！
You don't have
to run away.
逃げなくたって いいじゃねえか。
Come on,
Sakura-chan.
Die,
Wait!
ねぇ 死んでよ サクラちゃん。
逃げるのはやめて…。
- Stop it!
やめて… やめてよ！
Stop!
At this rate, the number of injured
will only continue to grow.
《いの : このままじゃ
ケガ人が増えるだけね。
We've got to find
a fundamental solution to this...
根本的な解決方法を
見つけないと…》
戦況は どうなってる？ いの！
How's the battle situation, Ino?
Shikamaru.
シカマル…。
(フエン)フフフフ… 毒蛾による幻覚で
落ちちゃったんだ。
She passed out from the illusion
caused by the poisonous moths.
I wonder what kind of dream
she's having.
いったい
どんな夢をみてるのかしら？
Well, nightmares suit little girls...
まぁ 小娘には
悪夢が お似合いだけど…。
Release!
(フエン)解！
Goodbye, little girl.
さようなら… お嬢ちゃん。
変わり身!?
A Substitution?
Goodbye, you sick jerk!
さよなら… 悪趣味野郎！
うっ！
な… なぜ 私の術が…!?
H-How did you escape my Jutsu?
The instant I heard your voice...
アンタの声を聞いた瞬間➡
I could pretty much guess
what you were going to do.
何をしてくるかは
だいたい想像がついたわ。
前は迷路に… 毒蜘蛛。
There was the poisonous spider
in the labyrinth before.
And this time,
you used poisonous moths.
そして 今度は毒蛾…。
I anticipated your attack pattern
and was prepared with a counter.
アンタの攻撃に備えて
シミュレーションはしてあった。
You gave yourself an antidote?
解毒剤を… 打っていた…。
You're evasive and
were never even on the battlefield.
(サクラ)姑息なアンタは
最初から勝負の場に立っていない。
The outcome of this fight was determined
from that moment on.
その時点で
勝敗は決まっていたのよ！
うわぁ～!!
あぁ…！
(リー)とぉ～っ！
(赤丸)ワンワン！
なんだ？
What?
The defense barrier...
防御結界が…。
消えていく…。
It's vanishing...
If the barrier is broken...
結界がとけたということは…➡
then has a detached unit
defeated the Jutsu caster?
別動隊が
術者を倒したのでしょうか!?
Even if that's the case,
だとしても
コイツらが消えてくれなきゃ➡
the situation won't change
if these guys don't go away.
状況は変わらねえしな。
Even so, the detached units
are very doing well!
(チョウジ)それでも
別動隊が がんばってるんだ！
We've got to take care of things
on our end, too!
ボクたちも なんとかしなくちゃね！
(シカマル)よく言った チョウジ。
Well said, Choji!
Shikamaru!
(チョウジ)シカマル！
This is a diversion.
(シカマル)ここは 陽動だ。
敵の狙いは別にある。
The enemy's objective is
probably elsewhere!
We've got to take care of things here
as quickly as possible
早いとこ ここを片づけて別動隊の
加勢に行かなきゃなんねえ。
and go back up the detached units.
We know that.
(ゲンマ)そんなことは
はなから わかってんだよ！
Stop complaining and come up
with a strategy!
グダグダ言ってねえで
とっとと作戦考えろ！
チッ… 人使いが あれえな。
What a slave driver!
Choji! You've got
some Chakra saved up, right?
チョウジ！
チャクラは温存してあんだろうな？
Yeah, all set. I can go anytime!
あぁ バッチリ！ いつでも行けるよ！
他の みんなは？
What about the rest of you guys?
I'm fit as a fiddle and ready to go!
青春バリバリ 真っただ中です！
I won't give in to youngsters!
まだまだ
若い者には負けませんぞ！
I was just thinking
I wanted to rampage like crazy!
思いっきり暴れたいと
思っていたところだ！
ワン ワン！
Yeah, us too!
(コテツ)オレたちもだよな…。
(イズモ)あ… あぁ。
Y-Yeah.
Okay then, let's go!
それじゃ いくぜ！
It's still too soon to
go beddy-bye, boy.
(フウカ)まだまだ寝んねには早いよ。
坊や！
Earth Style: Mud Silhouette!
土遁！ 泥法師!!
Water Style: Mouth of the Serpent!
水遁 邪の口！
The earth gains momentum from
the water and turns into a mudslide.
土は 水の勢いを得て
土石流となる。
フフフ…。
はぁ～っ!!
Eat this!
この～！
Let's fight for real already.
いいかげん マジメにやろうぜ。
Or are you going to
just run around forever?
いつまで逃げ回ってるつもりだ？
I'm not just running.
ただ逃げてるだけじゃないよ。
(フドウ)なに!?
What?
I was just waiting for the right conditions
for a counterattack.
ボクは ただ
反撃できる状況が整うまで➡
待ってただけのことなんだよ。
Water Style: Ripping Torrent!
水遁 破奔流！
Water Style?!
水遁だと!?
I should've been on alert for
the Water Style from a Wood Style user...
木遁使いなら
水遁も警戒するべきだったな。
But I won't be beaten so easily.
だが この程度じゃ
オレは やれんぞ。
You tilled the ground just right for me.
いい具合に
地面を耕してくれたよ。
Sandy soil, when broken down
into fine particles,
これだけ粉々になった砂地なら➡
absorbs water and liquefies
a lot easier.
水を吸って
液状化しやすいからね。
You jerk...
That was your plan from the start?
テメエ… 最初から そのつもりで…。
I don't need to take part in
an Earth Style battle to beat you.
土遁対決になんて
付き合う必要はないからね。
Wood Style: Tree Bind Eternal Burial!
木遁 樹縛永葬！
う… なんだ…。
Wh-What's this?!
木ノ葉の土となれ 土遁使い。
Become soil in the Leaf Village,
Earth Style user.
Nooo!
やめろ～!! うわ～！
Go, Choji!
いけ！ チョウジ！
Expansion Jutsu.
倍化の術！
Human Boulder!
肉弾戦車！
Next!
次！
いきます！
Here I go!
Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
そりゃ～！ 木ノ葉大旋風！
Next!
Man Beast Clone.
次！
獣人分身！ ん？
(シカマル)あ… これは いったい…。
What the hell is this?!
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
腹減った～。
シカマル 何か食いもん。
(シカマル)ねえよ バカ。
(チョウジ)ボク 持ってるよ。
おっ！ じゃあ くれよ チョウジ！
オッケー！ じゃあ ここで ボクの
オススメのお菓子を紹介しよう！
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
はい？
まずは…！
ガルＢポテート 豚の背脂味！
Next Episode
口の中に ドローッと広がる
背脂のギトギト感が最高！
Black clouds cover the sky and
roars of thunder reverberate.
The Hidden Leaf is close
to total destruction.
お次は ニンニクタブレット 忍鋤！
Friends scramble to avoid
the impending crisis.
新鮮なニンニクを たっぷり使った
さわやかな香り！
Yet, there is another impending crisis
amidst the chaos.
まさに 戦う男のスタミナ系タブレット！
The secret of Sora's origin will
at last be revealed.
続いて ガム・ザ・ホルモン！
噛んでも噛んでも 噛み切れない➡
Sora stands frozen in shock as Furido
reveals more about his terrible plan...
ホルモンの食感をリアルに再現した
ガム界の革命児！
Moment of Awakening
あ さらに ショコラマヨネーズ！
Next time:  "Moment of Awakening"
人気の食材 チョコとマヨネーズの…。
あぁ チョウジ もういいってばよ。
I'm hungry.
聞いてるだけで胸焼けしそうだぜ。
オレも…。
Shikamaru,
you got anything to eat?
No, you idiot.
そう？ おいしいのに…。
I've got some food.
Yeah! Give me some, Choji.
Okay!
Now I'll introduce
some snacks I recommend!
う～ん 幸せ！
— Huh?
— First!
Gal-B Potato Chips,
Pork Back Fat Flavor!
The greasy taste of the back fat
spreading inside your mouth is awesome!
Next are garlic tablets.
“Ninsukul”
These tablets are made with tons of
fresh garlic and have a brisk aroma.
They're stamina-type tablets
for fighting men, pure and simple!
Next is, “Entrail Gum”!
This revolutionary gum realistically
recreates the texture of entrails.
You can't chew through it
no matter how hard you try!
Next is, “Chocolate Mayonnaise”!
It's the dream pairing
of two popular foods,
- chocolate and mayonnaise.
- Enough already, Choji.
Huh?
I get heartburn just listening to that.
Me too.
Really? But it's so tasty...
Mmm, I'm so happy.